Wm Parker MacKenzie Principal Firmware Engineer

Passionate, dedicated, and versatile software engineer with experience in architecting, designing, and developing embedded system software. Capable of combining strong communication and interpersonal skills with a depth of technical knowledge when working with a team, leading a project, and communicating with customers. An extensive background working with cross functional hardware and software development teams.

Experience

Principal Firmware Engineer

Senet, Portsmouth NH

2015 – Present

- Designed, developed, and maintained a carrier grade multithreaded embedded Linux gateway application suite for managing and forwarding LoRa WAN packets between end devices and a cloud hosted server.
- Developed a cross development build system that allows the core applications to be ported to nearly a dozen different gateway platforms.
- Created and maintained the source control repositories which included a release management workflow based on Gitflow.
- Created close partnerships with gateway platform vendors; driving significant stability into the foundational system components.

Principal Software Systems Engineer

Extreme Networks (Acquisition of Enterasys), Salem NH

• Successfully lead the design and planning of a unified modular chassis combining key differentiating components from both companies.

2013 – 2015

- Researched and prototyped a multicore concurrent database soft switch-route-switch forwarding engine using the Freescale T-Series processor capable of flow setup rates of greater than one million packets per second. Researched porting the forwarding engine to the Cavium Octeon and EZ-Chip NPS series processor.
- Responsible for maintaining, optimizing, and adding features to the S and K series software forwarding path.

Senior/Principal Software Systems Engineer

Enterasys Networks, Andover MA

2007 – 2013

- Designed and developed a distributed software forwarding path for the S and K series modular switch-router system. Successfully used object-oriented design principles to balance performance, increase development velocity, and improve maintainability. The product was class leading and continues to ship today.
- Working closely with the hardware and FPGA/ASIC teams, designed and developed the modularity of the K-Series, this allowed for components of the switch fabric to be removed and inserted at runtime with no negative impact to the other fabric modules.

Senior Software Systems Engineer

2006 – 2007 Zhone Technologies, Portsmouth NH

• Transferred development of a DSL to ethernet switch to the Portsmouth office. Completed development, shipping on time and on budget.

2004 – 2006 Software Systems Engineer

Cabletron/Enterasys Networks, Rochester NH

Education

Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering University of Southern Maine, Portland ME

Personal Info

Address

PO Box 991

Kennebunk, ME 04043

Phone

207-229-6548

Web Site

wparkermackenzie.github.io

E-Mail

wparkermackenzie@outlook.com

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/wmackenzie

Development Languages

С	••••
	Excellent
C++	••••
	Excellent
Assembly	••••
-	Very Good
Bash	••••
	Very Good
Python	•••00
	Good
Perl	•••00
	Good

Skills

Algorithm Design Bare Metal Design

Concurrent Databases

Critical Path Optimization

Cross Platform Development

CVS

Distributed Systems

GDB

Git Gitflow

IoT Design

Linux Real Time Threading

Local Area Networking Standards

Logic Analyzers

LoRa WAN

Multi-core design

Object Oriented Design

On-chip Debuggers

OpenWRT

Oscilloscopes

Oscilloscopes

Poco C++ Libraries

RESTful Interfaces

Spectrum Analyzers

SSL/TLS

UML

VxWorks Development

Web Sockets

Yocto